is the dry weather that's been building
in Southwest Florida for months has led
to the worst drought we've seen in 25
years. WINK News reporter Bridget
Buchalski continues our team weather
coverage live now in Bonita Springs. And
Bridget, you spoke with a local nursery.
How have they held up with all this dry
weather?
Honestly, it's been a very tough season
for them. When it does get this dry and
we're not getting rain, these plants
need constant care. We're talking
watering in the morning, at night, even
throughout the day to keep up with this
Florida heat. So, when it does get this
dry and these drought conditions, these
plants won't be shy to tell you they
need some extra TLC.
It's so crazy, but if you really pay
attention, you can see your flower sad.
They kind of almost weep over. They kind
of start hanging. They look really
sluggish. You'll see the leaves starting
to curl. But, those are kind of like the
top telltale signs. That's when the
drought starts to show its face. At San
Juan Family Nursery, Ariely San Juan
knows the struggle all too well.
>> When we do go through periods of
drought, that's when we typically see
that plants that may need more water
tend to kind of wither a little bit. We
kind of attack that well while also
trying to be more conservative with our
water usage. For some plants this
season, they honestly just had to be
thrown away. Then, when it comes to
regrowing them to kind of be ready for
sale, you kind of get backtracked a lot
now with the drought.
>> Why does this year feel different? It's
completely normal to go into drought
during dry season. The question is, how
early in the season you fall into
drought? WINK Weather Authority
meteorologist Katie Walls explains. We
went into dry season a foot below
average. Then, our dry season,
especially toward the end of 2025, was
exceptionally low, exceptionally dry. We
were receiving maybe about 40% of our
average rainfall during dry season.
Here's a comparison. On the left, right
now, all of Southwest Florida is in the
extreme red zone. On the right, this
time last year, most of the region was
in severe drought with Bonita Springs
and Naples in extreme. So, how much rain
does it take to dig us out?
>> We need 19 inches to catch up. We're
talking more than a foot and a half. We
might not see that really begin to
improve significantly until later in
June.
>> Back at the nursery, we are hoping to
get some rain in the mix, kind of get
some wetness to kind of lift up that
hotness and the humidity. And more than
anything, just trying to take care of
our plants as best as we can.
Luckily, we are going to get some rain
here in Bonita Springs and across Lee
County. So, coming up, we're going to be
having a live coverage in your
neighborhood tracking those raindrops.
I'm live in Bonita Springs, Bridget
Buchalski, WINK News.
All right, thank you very much, Bridget.